Guide to the Fred Chappell Papers, 1944-2019 and undated RL.00213
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accessions, 1993-2018
  - Accession (2012-0031), 5 boxes
    - Writings by Others (Box 2)
      - Separation sheets, detailing volumes removed for individual cataloging, 1 folder (Box 2)
      - Bound volumes and journals, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Poetry: Fort, Charles, 1 folder (Box 2)
      - Poetry: Owens, Scott, 1 folder (Box 3)
      - Poetry: Various Authors, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Prose: Howell, Ross, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Prose: Knopp, Brian Lee, 1 folder (Box 3)
      - Prose: Senehi, Rose, folder 1 of 2 (Box 3)
      - Prose: Senehi, Rose, folder 2 of 2 (Box 4)
      - Prose: Various Authors, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Events and Publicity (Box 4)
      - 2010, 1 folder (Box 4)
        - Caldwell Award ceremony audio recordings and photographs, 2010; 2 disk images derived from optical discs and 173 image files; approximately 1.3 gigabytes.
        - Chattahoochee Review interview audio recording, 2010; 1 disk image derived from optical disc; approximately 4.5 gigabytes.
      - Spring 2011, 1 folder (Box 4)
      - Winter 2011, 1 folder (Box 4)
      - 2012 and Undated, 1 folder (Box 4)
      - 2011 North Carolina Literary Festival poster (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Stirring the Silence audio recording, circa 2007; Disk image derived from optical disc; approximately 88 megabytes.
      Includes audio recording of Stirring the Silence, a choral piece, containing words by by Fred Chappell and music by Dan Locklair.
  - Accession (2013-0036), 3 boxes
    Addition 2013-0036 includes incoming and outgoing correspondence; writings by other authors; published materials by Chappell; and prose and poetry drafts by Chappell.
    - Writings by Others (Box 1)
      - Various Authors (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Ellen Beinhorn (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Renee Soto (Box 1)
      - Poetry: David Radavich (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Rob Neufeld (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Llwellyn McKernan (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Ted Olson (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Elizabeth Seydel Morgan (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Ed M. Schorb (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Fritz Porter (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Julia Nunnally Duncan (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Bill Walsh (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Vincent S. Kelly Jr. (Box 1)
      - Poetry: Janice Hornburg (Box 1)
      - Music: Dana Wildsmith (Box 1)
      - Prose: Kelly Cherry (Box 1)
      - Prose: David Madden (Box 1)
      - Prose: O'Henry Magazine Short Story Contest Finalists (Box 1)
      - Prose: Florence Gatten (Box 1)
      - Prose: Harold A. Lloyd (Box 1)
      - Prose: Catharine Savage Brosman (Box 1)
    - Artwork (Box 1)
      - Janschka (Box 1)
    - Events and Publicity (Box 1)
      - 2012 (Box 1)
    - Printed Materials (Box 1)
      - O'Henry Magazine, Nov. 2012 and North Carolina Conversations, Summer/Fall 2011 (Box 1)
      - North Carolina Society Annual Report, 2011-2012 and Chronicles, June 2012 (Box 1)
      - Revelations: Poems by Ted Olson (Box 2)
      - Eating the Heart First: Poems by Clare L. Martin (Box 2)
      - Hitchcock's Coffin: Sonnets about Classic Films by Kim Bridgeford (Box 2)
      - Between Here and Monkey Mountain: Poems by Laren McClung (Box 2)
      - A Bird Black as the Sun: California Poets on Crows & Ravens (Box 2)
      - Russian Language Magazine, September 2012 (Box 2)
      - My Thoughts Prefer Side Streets: Collected Essays and Other Reflections by Leslie Miklosy (Box 2)
      - Fantasy & Science Fiction, May/June 2012 (Box 2)
    - Writings by Chappell (Box 1)
      - Published Writings by Chappell
        - "The Collector: On the Occasion of the Opening of the Stuart Wright Exhibit" in North Carolina Literary Review, 2012 (2 copies) (Box 1)
        - The Idea of Story Ideas" in Eudora Welty Review, Vol. 4: Spring 2012 (Box 1)
        - "Things Beyond Us" in The Sewanee Review, Winter 2012 (Box 1)
      - Drafts & Notes by Chappell (Box 2)
        - Spiral Notebook (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Shadow Box (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Peace, Diversity (Box 2)
        - Poetry: From Here to There, Motley (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Watchers, At Forest Edge, and the Forest's Story (Box 2)
        - Poetry: The Jitters, Pillow Talk, The Feast in the Cave (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Malka Guides (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Moonwort (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Difference, White Out (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Cousin Lilias, Genius Loci (Box 2)
        - Poetry: The Book, The Sign, and The Riddle (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Rinalfo, His Story, After Hours, Ars Gratia Artis (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Objectivity, Snowflake, Morris Revisited (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Pastorale, A Last Glimpse of the Traveler (Box 2)
        - Poetry: Forest Series (Box 2)
        - Prose: The Shadows of Forgetting (Box 2)
        - Prose: The White Cat (Box 2)
        - Prose: Horror Remarks, Scallion (Box 2)
        - Prose: Curly Claus (Box 2)
        - Prose: Shadow of the Jester (Box 2)
        - Prose: Shadows of the Past (Box 2)
        - Prose: Keynote Address for Literary Gathering at UNCG (April 2012) (Box 2)
        - Prose: Gathering of Shadows (Box 2)
        - Prose: The Absent Shadows, Bob Watson (Box 2)
        - Prose: Thief of Shadows (Box 2)
        - Prose: The Diamond Shadow (Box 2)
        - Prose: Dance of Shadows (Box 2)
        - Prose: The Creeper Shadows (Box 2)
        - Prose: Philadelphia Lecture, Mixing Memory and Desire (Box 2)
        - Prose: Uncle Moon in Raintee Hills (Box 2)
        - Prose: Shadow of the Valley (Box 2)
        - Prose: The Shadows Among Us (Box 2)
        - Prose: Shadow of the Turnip (Box 2)
        - Prose: Hooyoo Love, The Idea of Story Ideas, and Tribute to Ehle (Box 2)
        - Prose: Various (Box 2)
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
      - Newsletters (Box 2)
      - Invitations & Events (Box 2)
      - Chappell Responses 2012-January 2013, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Undated (2012-2013?), 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Royalty Statements (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, 2002-2011 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, January 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, February 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, March 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, April 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, May 2012, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, June 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, July 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, August 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, September 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, October 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, November 2012 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, December 2012, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, January 2013 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, February 2013 (Box 3)
      - Outgoing, March 2013 (Box 3)
  - Accession (2014-0128), 1960-2014; 9.5 Linear Feet
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 2013-2014
      - Mar-Aug 2013 (Box 1)
      - Sept 2013-Feb 2014, 2013-2014 (Box 1)
      - Mar-Jul 2014 (Box 1)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1980-2014
      - 1980s (Box 1)
      - 1990s (Box 1)
      - 2000s (Box 1)
      - 2011-2012 (Box 1)
      - Jan 2013 (Box 1)
      - Feb 2013 (Box 1)
      - Mar 2013, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Apr 2013, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - May 2013, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Jun 2013, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Jul 2013, 3 folders (Box 1-2)
      - Aug 2013, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Sept 2013, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Oct 2013, 4 folders (Box 2-3)
      - Nov 2013, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Dec 2013, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Jan 2014 (Box 3)
      - Feb 2014, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Mar 2014, 3 folders (Box 3-4)
      - Apr 2014, 3 folders (Box 4)
      - May 2014, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Jun 2014, 4 folders (Box 4)
      - undated, 4 folders (Box 4-5)
    - Clippings
      - 1960s (Box 5)
      - 1970s (Box 5)
      - 1980s (Box 5)
      - 1990s (Box 5)
      - 2000s (Box 5)
      - undated (Box 5)
    - Writings
      - undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - "Familiars" drafts (Box 5)
      - "Thief of Shadows" (Box 5)
      - journals (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Awards (Box 5)
      - Coat of Arms, undated (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 5)
      - Program Brochures (Box 5)
      - Receipts (Box 5)
      - Appalachian Heritage, 2013; 1 serial (Box 6)
      - Lovecraft's Monsters, 2014; 1 monograph (Box 6)
      - Succinct: The Broadstone Anthology of Short Poems, 2013; 1 monograph (Box 6)
      - The Collected Poems of Cathy Smith Bowers, 2013; 1 monograph (Box 6)
      - International Poetry Review, Fall 2013; 1 serial (Box 6)
      - Modern Age: A quarterly review, 2012; 1 serial (Vol. 5) (Box 6)
      - Award Statue, 2013 (Box 6)
      - North Carolina Literary Review, 2013-2014; 2 items 2 serials (no. 22 & 23) (Box 7)
      - O'Henry: The Art and Soul of Greensboro, 2013-2014; 3 items 3 serials (Apr 2013, Sept 2013, Jun 2014) (Box 7)
      - Salt: The Ar and Soul of Wilmington, 2013-2014; 2 items 2 serials (Jul 2013, Jun 2014) (Box 7)
  - Accession (2014-0209), 1973-2014
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - April-June 2014 (Box 1)
      - July 2014 (Box 1)
      - July 2014 (Box 1)
      - July 2014 (Box 1)
      - August 2014 (Box 1)
      - August 2014 (Box 1)
      - September 2014 (Box 1)
      - September 2014 (Box 1)
      - October 2014 (Box 1)
      - October 2014 (Box 1)
      - November 2014 (Box 1)
      - December 2014 (Box 1)
      - Undated (Box 1)
    - Outgoing Correspondence
      - March 2014 (Box 1)
    - Writings by Chappell
      - Drafts and Notes: Poetry (Box 1)
    - Events and Publicity
      - 2014 (Box 1)
    - Clippings
      - June 2013 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Awards 2012 (Box 1)
    - Legal and Financial Papers
      - Contracts 1973-1992 (Box 1)
      - Contracts 1993-1998 (Box 1)
      - Contracts 2000-2008 (Box 2)
      - Contracts, undated (Box 2)
    - Writings by Others
      - Music (Box 2)
      - Printed Material
        - Big Cactus, A novel by Sylvia Wilkinson (Box 2)
        - The Door of Sad People, A novel by Alexander Blackburn (Box 2)
        - Glimmerglass, A novel by Matrly Yumatns (Box 2)
        - Driving with the Dead, Poems by Jane Hicks (Box 2)
        - Wallomsac by David R. Slavitt (Box 2)
        - Shiksa, Poems by David R. Slavitt (Box 2)
        - Dancing on Rocks, a novel by Rose Senehi (Box 2)
        - Love and Other Hungers, Poems by Susan O'Dell Underwood (Box 2)
        - The Catholic Writer Today by Dana Gioia (Box 2)
        - Steal Away, Poems by Shelby Stephenson (Box 2)
        - Beyond Fairy Tales, Poems by Maureen A. Sherbondy (Box 2)
        - The Dog Killer of Utica, A novel by Frank Lentricchia (Box 2)
        - The Last Bizarre Tale, Stories by David Madden (Box 2)
        - Like a Beggar, Poems by Ellen Bass (Box 2)
        - For I Am Mountainborn, Poems by Lenore McComas Coberly (Box 2)
        - A Dignified Life by Virginia Bell, David Troxel (Box 2)
        - I Understand and Wish to Continue, Poems by Travis R. Venters (Box 2)
        - Lost in the White Ruins, Poems by William Walsh (Box 2)
        - Walzting with Horses, Poems by Felicia Mitchell (Box 3)
        - On the Old Plaza, Poems by Catherine Savage Brosman (Box 3)
        - Love and Extraordinary Creatures, A novel by Gwyn Hyman Rubio (Box 3)
        - Shub's Cooking, Poems by Shelby Stephenson (Box 3)
        - The Dream of Saint Ursula by Kenneth Butcher (Box 3)
        - All Night it is Morning, Poems by Andy Young (Box 3)
        - Motor City Running, A novel by Bill Morris (Box 3)
        - Changing Seasons, Poetry by the Seasoned Poets of the Blue Ridge (Box 3)
        - Rock and Sling, a journal of witness (Box 3)
      - Poetry
        - Charles Fort (Box 3)
        - David R. Slavitt (Box 3)
        - Jeanette Rogers (Box 3)
        - Greg Kuzma (Box 3)
      - Prose
        - Raymond Barfield (Box 3)
        - Various authors, A Gallery of Ashevillians (Box 3)
        - Kenneth Butcher (Box 3)
        - Kelly Cherry (Box 3)
        - Warren Rochelle (Box 3)
        - Will Morgan (Box 3)
  - Accession (2015-0134), 2013-2015; 6.0 Linear Feet
    - Incoming correspondence, 2014 Oct.-2015 Oct. and undated; 2 boxes (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 1, Box Acc. 15/134: Box 2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 2014 July-2015 Sept.; 1 boxes (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 2)
    - Chappell's drafts and notes: Notebooks, undated (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 2)
    - "A Shadow All of Light," edited manuscripts, 2014-2015; 6 folders (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 2, Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
      Includes 3 versions of the novel spread across 2 boxes.
    - Chappell's poetry manuscripts, undated (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - Chappell's miscellaneous writings, 2015 and undated (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - List of publications, interviews, readings, etc., 2014-2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - 27 Views of Greensboro: The Gate City in Prose & Poetry (Hillsborough, NC: Eno Publishers), 2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - Masters of the Weird Tale (Lakewood, CO: Centipede Press), 2014 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - Dagon (Milan, Italy: Arnoldo Mondadori Editore S.P.A.), 2014 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - Three Poems & Two Essays (Berrien Springs, MI: St. Andrews University Press), 2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - Now & Then. The Appalachian Magazine. The Best of Thirty Years. Part I (1984-1999) (Vol. 30, No. 2), 2015 Winter (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 3)
    - The Southern Poetry Anthology. Volume VII: North Carolina (Huntsville, TX: Texas Review Press), 2014 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - Black Wings IV. New Tales of Lovecraftian Horror (Hornsea, UK: PS Publishing Ltd), 2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - best of asheville poetry review (Vol. 21, no. 1, 2014, issue 24) (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - Amazing Place. What North Carolina Means to Writers (Chapel Hill, NC: The University of North Carolina Press), 2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - The Sewanne Review (Spring 2015, Volume CXXIII, Number 2), 2015 Spring (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - A Kelly Cherry Reader. Selected Stories, Novel Excerpts, Essays, Memoir, and Poetry (Nacogdoches, TX: Stephen F. Austin State University Press), 2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous drafts and notes by others, 2014-2015 and undated; 13 folders (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous published writings by others, 1999-2015; 34 Volumes (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - Chappell's miscellaneous events and publicity, 2015 and undated (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - The North Caroliniana Society, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
    - Chappell's royalty statements, 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 15/134: Box 4)
  - Accession (2016-0235), 1985-2016, 5 Linear Feet
    Addition 2016-0235 includes incoming and outgoing correspondence; prose and poetry drafts by Chappell; typescript drafts by other authors; published materials by other writers. Also includes one folder of oversize materials.
    - Incoming correspondence, May 2015 to August 2016, 21 folders (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, September 2015- August 2016, 2 folders (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
    - Chappell's royalty statements, 2014-2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
    - Events
      - Bookmarks Festival, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - North Carolina Society event to honor Fred Chappell, 2007 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Event calendar, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Speeches and bookstore presentations, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Assorted printed materials: literary magazines, newspapers, annual reports received by Chappell (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
    - Writings
      - Dagon, Italian translation, 2014 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Poem drafts, 2016, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Memorials, 2016, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Other writings, drafts, 2016, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Notebooks with drafts and notes, undated; 2 folders (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - A Shadow All of Light, typescript drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - A Shadow All of Light, edited typescript, undated; 4 folders (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - A Shadow all of Light, galley proof typescript, undated; 2 folders (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Drafts for Red Truck Review, December 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Jim Clark, 1997-2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
    - Writings by Others
      - Harriet Wolf's Seventh book of Wonders, Julianna Baggott, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - The Levees that Break in the Heart, Ivan Broughton, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - More Frailer than Flowers, Nancy Dillingham, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Dawn to Twilight, Daniel Mark Epstein, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - 99 Poems, New and Selected, Dana Gioia, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Poetry as Enchantment, Dana Gioia, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 2)
      - Winter Inlet, Hasings Hensel, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Lake Erie's Shores and Islands, H. John and Marie Hildebrandt, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Forsaken, Ross Howell Jr., 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - A Place to Dig, Herb Jackson, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Black Wings of Cthulhu 4, edited by S.T. Joshi, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - A Manner of Being, edited by Annie Liontas, Jeff Parker, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Poetic Gems, William McGonagall, 1985 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Outside the Gates of Eden, 2014 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Travelers Rest, Keith Lee Morris, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Hiccups, Joe Pan, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Original Face, Jim Peterson, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Chinua Achebe: Teacher of Light, Tijan M. Sallah and Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala, 2003 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Dreams of Dusty Roads, Tijan M. Sallah, 1993 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Magic Again, edited by David Radavich, David Strange, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Hundred Year Wave, Rachel Richardson, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - That Bright Land, Terry Roberts, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - The Road to Ballyvaughan, Gibbons Ruark, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Elegies for Small Game, Shelby Stephenson, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Only the One Sky, Dabney Stuart, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - Time's Body, Dabney Stuart, 2014 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 3)
      - A Matter of Blood, Kermit Turner, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - The Blue Hour, Jennifer Whitaker, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - My Christmas memory, Ted Wojtasik, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Maze of Blood, Mary Youmans, 2015 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Chopsticks on the Ukelele, galley proof typescript, Darin Cozzens, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - The Gogol Notebook draft, Angela Davis-Gardener, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Loners and Mothers typescript, Allen Ireland, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Bi-Blues typescript, Greg Kuzma, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Two short story typescripts, Frank Lentricchia, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Cross Cypress typescript, Guy Lillian, undated (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Wins and Losses typescript, Peter Makuck, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Fire is Your Water typescript, Jim Minick, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - The Werewolf and His Boy galley proof typescript, Warren Rochelle, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - The Traveling Exquisites typescript, R. M. Ryan, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
      - Tidelines typescript, Russell Steinke, 2016 (Box Acc. 16/0235: Box 4)
    - Broadside of Susan O'Dell Underwood's poem "Holler" (Oversize-folder Acc. 16/0235: Ovsz folder 1)
    - Cover of A Shadow All of Light (Oversize-folder Acc. 16/0235: Ovsz folder 1)
  - Accession (2017-0075), 1990s-2017 and undated
    - Incoming correspondence, 2016 Feb.-2017 May and undated; 19 Files (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 2016 Aug.-2017 May; 2 folders (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 2)
    - Writings by others, B-K, 2014-2016; 16 folders (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 2)
      Drafts and published works by other authors and poets, sent to or collected by Chappell. Files are arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Writings by others, K-W, 2014-2016; 16 folders (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Poetry drafts by Chappell, 2016-2017 and undated; 2 folders (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Prose drafts by Chappell, undated (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Lecture and speech drafts by Chappell, 2016-2017 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - NC Writers' Network, 2016-2017 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - National Women's History Project, 2016 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - North Caroliniana Society, 2016 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Public ceremonies and events photographs, 2010s and undated (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Fritz Janschka Celebration, 2016 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Clippings, other press coverage of Chappell, 1990s-2016 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Awards and honors, 1999, 2016 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 3)
    - Separated audiovisual materials, 2016 (Box Acc. 17/075: Box 4)
  - Accession (2018-0109), 1950s-2018
    Addition includes routine correspondence between Chappell and his fellow writers and friends, 2017-2018, as well as a set of clippings and other letters between Chappell and his family (largely his parents) dating from the 1960s-1980s. Clippings are largely reviews of Chappell's early work; profiles of Chappell in various newspapers; and event publicity for his appearances.
    The addition also contains drafts of Chappell's poetry, essays, and forthcoming book, As If It Were. There are exchanges between Chappell and Angela Davis-Gardner documenting his research and reflections as he wrote an essay about her work. This materials is accompanied by writings and poetry (both published and in-progress) sent to Chappell by other authors and friends for review or comment. Includes set of 2000s correspondence between Susan Chappell and Stuart Wright. Items in this accession are loosely sorted and most correspondence remains in original envelopes.
    - Writings by others, A-W, 2010s (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 1)
    - A World Assembly of Poets: Re-Markings poetry anthology (with Chappell's contributions), 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 1)
    - "Tiros II" in The Paris Review, 1963 Fall (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Greenlyn Forest manuscript, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Greensboro Bound opening remarks, 2018 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Enlightenment Fables poetry drafts (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Remembering Joe Powlosky, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Gaylor Callahan memorial, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - As If It Were, 2017-2018; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
      Contains reader reports, correspondence with LSU Press, and drafts and proofs with Chappell's edits.
    - A Salutation to the Alma Mater in this Her Birth Year, 2017 Fall (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
      Published in UNCG Magazine; file includes Chappell's edits on the magazine.
    - Rotten Cucumbers draft (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Children Fated to Search: The Novels of Angela Davis-Gardner, 2017-2018; 3 Files (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
      Research, 4 of Gardner-Davis's novels, correspondence with AGD, and drafts by Chappell.
    - "About 2 weeks after I heard..." Asheville Poetry Review tribute to Kathryn Stripling Byer, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - "Fablests" and other poems, drafts, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - The Wasp and the Snake, published in Modern Age, 2017 Fall (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Poetry drafts, unsorted, 2017; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Untitled spiral notebook with drafts, diary entries, and reading schedules, 1957 and undated (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Notebooks with drafts (poetry and prose), 2017 and undated (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)
    - Publications (list) by Chappell, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/109: Box 2)